(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T18:15:47.249114",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
理性の中で鳴り響く スタートの合図
The start signal echoing within my reason,
何度だって全部結んだ 世界色付けてく ここから
coloring the world tied together time and time again, starting from here.
かくれんぼ
Kakurenbo
もの心付く頃 すでにここにいた
By the time I was aware of things, I was already here.
いぜーのーで鳴り響いた
Ready, set, go! The cue signal
スタートの合図
for start resounds.
なぞった線で結んだ世界
The world bound by the traced line,
色付けていくここから
I'll add color to it from here on.
物心がつくだろう頃には此処にあった
Long before I could even remember, it was right here.
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は夕日とともに蘇る
Memories not my own revive along with the setting sun.
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して落書きの中に1つの答えを見つけた
I take out an old picture book and find an answer hidden within the doodles.
自分の価値に目を疑って
Doubting my own worth,
どこまでだって墜ちていけるの
just how far can I fall?
どこか遠くに消してしまいたい
I want to disappear somewhere far away.
こんな世界じゃ僕はいらない
In a world like this, I'm not needed.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun!
“いぜーのーで”声上げて
Raising my voice with a "ready, set, go!"
聞こえてくるかくれんぼ
I hear the game of hide-and-seek.
君を見つけ出すよ 君に会いにいくよ
I'll find you out, I'm going to see you.
オレンジ夕日 帰っていく 歌いながら
The orange sunset, walking back home while singing,
電信柱の影踏んで 帰るふりをしていた
stepping on utility pole shadows, pretending to head home.
得意の道草しても 人遊びして
Even taking my usual detour, playing around,
公園貸し切り「かくれんぼ」 帰らない5時までは
the park all to myself for "hide-and-seek" until 5 o'clock.
鬼決めジャンケン！伸びてく影 赤い鬼になって
Rock, paper, scissors to choose the demon! Shadows stretching, becoming the red demon,
つぶした目 背中じゅうから消えてく声「もういいよ！」
eyes closed, with the fading voice from behind: "Ready or not!"
一番近くにいる君に 一番隠してた
Being closest to you, I was hiding the most.
一番早く見つけたくて
I wanted to find you the quickest.
広いこの空の下 小っちさい胸の中で
Under this vast sky, within my tiny heart,
神様だけは知ってた 照れくさかった
only God knew—how embarrassed I was.
何より誰より隠してた 君を好きな気持ち
More than anyone else, I hid my feelings for you.
滑り台の下の頬 影が一つ
The shadow on my cheek under the slide is just one.
バレバレなのに見えないふり この気持ち 恋心
Even though it's so obvious, I pretend not to see—this feeling, this love.
昔はあんなに 爪噛んだり 指を鳴らしたり
Back then, you used to bite your nails or crack your knuckles,
今はもう君の癖さえ 過去形でも「大好き！」
and now even your habits, even in the past tense, I love you!
どんなに遠くに離れても どんなに隠れても
No matter how far apart we drift, no matter how well you hide,
どんなに小さく静かでも かくれてる？
no matter how small and quiet, are you hiding?
「かくしてる！」初恋の「かくれんぼ」
"I'm hiding!" The hide-and-seek of first love.
一番近くにいる君に 一番隠してた
Being closest to you, I was hiding the most.
一番早く見つけたくて 遠い・おさない・想い
I wanted to find you the quickest—distant, childish thoughts.
どんなに遠くに離れても どんなに隠れても
No matter how far apart we drift, no matter how well you hide,
どんなに小さく静かでも
no matter how small and quiet,
一直線で駆け抜ける君 靴擦れてただけの僕でも
Running straight ahead, you—even with just my blistered shoes,
君の前を歩けるかな こんな頼りない僕でも
can I walk ahead of you, even as unreliable as I am?
僕は埃をかったまま無くした
I lost it while covered in dust,
鍵はずっと君のポケットの中にあった
the key had always been inside your pocket.
散らばってた全てが今ひとつに重なる
Everything that was scattered now overlaps into one.
手を取り始めよう僕たちの物語
Let's join hands and start our story.
どんなに遠くに離れても どんなに隠れても
No matter how far apart we drift, no matter how well you hide,
どんなに小さく静かでも かくれてる？
no matter how small and quiet, are you hiding?
「かくしてる！」初恋の「かくれんぼ」
"I'm hiding!" The hide-and-seek of first love.
一番近くにいる君に 一番隠してた
Being closest to you, I was hiding the most.
一番早く見つけたくて 遠い・おさない・想い
I wanted to find you the quickest—distant, childish thoughts.
どんなに遠くに離れても どんなに隠れても
No matter how far apart we drift, no matter how well you hide,
どんなに小さく静かでも
no matter how small and quiet,
ずっと終わらないから ずっと忘れないから
it will never end, I will never forget—
初恋の「かくれんぼ」
the hide-and-seek of first love.
もう一回 まただよ
Once again, not yet!
泣き叫ぶ声で
With a crying, shouting voice,
もう一回 まただよ
once again, not yet!
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling.
もう一回 まただよ
Once again, not yet!
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has risen.
もう一回 もういいよ色付けてくここから
Once again, ready or not, I'll add color from here on!
暑天 作詞・作曲: 氏原ワタル
[Song: Shoten / Lyrics & Music: Wataru Ujihara]
沈むように溶けていくように
Like sinking, like melting away...
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
On a night when only the two of us could see the sky
「さよなら」だけだった
It was just "goodbye."
その一言で全てが分かった
That one word made everything clear.
日が沈み出した空と君の姿 フェンス越しに重なっていた
The setting sun and your figure overlapped across the fence.
初めて会った日から 僕の心の全てを奪った
From the day we first met, you stole everything from my heart.
どこか儚い空気を纏う君は 寂しい目をしていたんだ
You, who had a somewhat ephemeral aura about you, your eyes were lonely.
いつだってチックタックと鳴る世界で何回だってさ
In a world that always ticks, no matter how many times...
触れる心無い言葉うるさい声に涙零れそうでも
Even when tears threaten to fall from the heartless words and annoying voices,
ありきたりの喜びきっと二人なら見つけられる
We can surely find ordinary joy if it's the two of us.
騒がしい日々に笑えない君に
To you who can't smile in these noisy days,
思い付く限り眩しい明日を
I'll give you the brightest tomorrow I can imagine.
明けない夜に落ちていく前に 僕の手を掴んでほしかった
Before you fall into the endless night, grab my hand, come on.
忘れてしまいたくて閉じ込めた日も
Even the days you locked away, wanting to forget them,
抱きしめた温もりで溶かすから
I'll melt them away with the warmth of my embrace.
怖くないよいつか日が昇るまで二人でいよう
Don't be afraid, let's be together until the sun rises someday.
君にしか見えない 何かを見つめる君が嫌いだ
I hate you when you stare at something only you can see.
見惚れているかのような 恋するような そんな顔が嫌いだ
That look on your face, like you're mesmerized, like you're in love...
信じてたいけど信じられないこと そんなのどうしたってきっと
Things I want to believe but can't, no matter what, I'm sure.
これからだっていくつもあって そのたび怒って泣いていくの
Even from now on, there are so many, and each time I get angry and cry.
それでもきっといつかはきっと僕らはきっと分かり合えるさ信じているよ
But I'm sure someday, surely, we'll understand each other, I believe.
もう嫌だって疲れたんだって がむしゃらに差し伸べた僕の手を振り払う君
"I've had enough, I'm tired," you brush away my hand that I desperately reach out to you.
もう嫌だって疲れたよなんて 本当は僕も言いたいんだ
"I've had enough, I'm tired," I really want to say that too.
ああ、もうチックタックと鳴る世界で何回だってさ
Ah, look, tick-tock again, in this world that ticks over and over again,
君の為にご用意した言葉どれも届かない
None of the words I prepared for you reach you.
「終わりにしたい」なんてさ 釣られて言葉にした時 君は初めて笑った
"I want to end it," when I said it, caught up in the moment, you smiled for the first time.
騒がしい日々に笑えなくなっていた 僕の目に映る君は綺麗だ
I hadn't been able to smile in these noisy days, but you look beautiful in my eyes.
明けない夜に溢れた涙も 君の笑顔に溶けていく
Even the tears that fell in the never-ending night melt away in your smile.
変わらない日々に出て泣いていた僕を 君は優しく終わりへと誘う
You gently lead me to the end.
沈むように溶けていくように 染み付いた霧が晴れる
As if sinking, as if melting away, the ingrained mist clears.
忘れてしまいたくて閉じ込めた日々に 差し伸べてくれた君の手を取る
In the days I locked away, wanting to forget, I take the hand you reached out to me.
涼しい風が空を泳ぐように今吹き抜けていく 繋いだ手を離さないでよ
Like a cool breeze, the wind blows through. Don't let go of my hand.
二人今、夜に駆け出していく
We're running out into the night together now.
放っておいて育つものなんだ なんたんだろう?
Something that grows when you leave it alone - what is it?
なんだなんだろう ももちゃん ももちゃん never never give up!
Nene, Nene, never never give up!
ももちゃん ももちゃん never give up!
Nene, Nene, never give up!
出会いましては簡単すぎるよ 最初にと決めた答えはひとつ
Meeting someone else is easy to do, I’ve decided the answer first at the beginning.
ときめきました合格しますか? 恋も勝負もあわてない
My heart throbs—did I pass? I won’t be flustered in love or matches.
コツコツコツと徹夜にため息 私の中に天才dreamer
Study, study, study and sighing all night, I’m a genius dreamer inside me.
想うことみな叶えばいいな 他人の世界は気にしない
It’d be great if everyone’s wishes come true. I won’t worry about other people's worlds.
Perfect-area complete! 絶対ここで待ってるんだ
Perfect-area complete! I’m definitely waiting here.
Perfect-area 望む声が聞こえるよ あ! EAR EAR!!
Perfect-area, I hear the voice I desire, ah, ear, ear!
Why? とまらないすれ違い 私が相談相手なら
Why? I won’t stop, and we pass each other by. If I’m your confidante,
「友達かい?」「友達です。」 悲しき0点だね
"Are we friends?" "Yes, we are." It’s a sad score of 0.
No! やりなおしかいなおし 本気で one more chance please
No! I’ll redo it and rewrite it. I’m serious, one more chance, please!
いまより素敵な未来があるのに いまより素敵に my life, my life, my life!!
From now, a better future is awaiting—more wonderful than now is my life, my life, my life!
願いましたよ月にも星にも 科学的にはどうにもならず
I wished upon the moon and upon the stars, but scientifically, I couldn’t do anything about it.
かがやき増したあしたを夢見て 恋でガマンを学んだね
I dreamed of tomorrow, whose brightness increased, and I learned of patience with love.
ムクムクムクと広がる雨雲 私をぬらす瞬間squall
Bit by bit, the rain clouds spread, and I’m wet because of a sudden squall.
悩みごとほら流れたみたい 泣きごとなんて忘れようよ
It’s like all of my worries, look, are washed away. Let’s forget about our complaints!
Passive-nature conversation! 感動したいもっとずっと
Passive-nature conversation! I want to move you, more and always.
Passive-nature 自分次第変われるよ hi! EAR EAR!!
Passive-nature, I can change by my own choice, hi, ear, ear!
はーいいーや、わー！
Ha-i-ya, wa!
さりげなく聞いてみた
Casually, I asked,
私の勉強不足で 可能性ありますか？
"With my lack of studying, is there any possibility?"
試験は何点かな？ イェー！
"What's my test score? Yeah!"
誰だって 君だって 巡り合う日が来るよ
Anyone, even you, the day we meet will come.
これから始まる 季節に挨拶
Greeting the season starting from now on,
これから始まる マイ・マイ・マイライフ！
Starting from now, my, my, my life!
気づいた時には 生まれてた なぜだろう
By the time I noticed, I was born... Why is that?
そうね 意識は もう育ちつつあるよ
That's right, my consciousness is already growing,
強く 強く ねぇ！ 止まらない この気持ち
Strongly, strongly, hey! This feeling won't stop!
まいとまらない この気持ち
My, it won't stop, this feeling,
私の勉強不足で
with my lack of studying,
可能性ありますか？
is there any possibility?
それともレッドカード？
Or a red card?
No! やりのむち かきのむち
No! Spear whip, oyster whip,
本気ではまんじゃり
seriously engrossed,
今より素敵な未来があるから
because there's a future even more wonderful than now,
今より素敵に マイ・マイ・マイライフ！
even more wonderfully now, my, my, my life!
はい！というわけで始まりました！
Yes! So, it has begun!
2026年！桃鈴ねね誕生日、イェーイ！
Year 2026! Momosuzu Nene's birthday, Yay!
みんなコメントも見えてるよ、ありがとう！
I can see everyone's comments too, thank you!
はい、というわけで今回の初タグはこちら！
Well then, the first hashtag for this time is here!
「#桃鈴ねね誕生ライブ2026」です！
"#MomosuzuNeneBirthdayLive2026"!
今日はね、超重大告知があるので最後まで楽しんでいってください！
Today, there's a super big announcement, so please enjoy until the end!
さあ、いま3曲お届けいただいたんですけど、
Now, we've delivered 3 songs so far,
ねねの好きな曲……銀魂とかバカテスっていう感じでね、もうねねの好きな曲しかない3曲をやりましたけど、
Nene's favorite songs... Gintama, Baka and Test, and the like. We did 3 songs that are strictly Nene's favorites,
3曲目に一番、歌がキツいの持ってきちゃって
and for the 3rd song, I brought the hardest one to sing,
ゼハゼハでございます！それではここからはゲストパート入っていきます！
leaving me gasping for breath! Well then, from here on we enter the guest part!
抱きしめたいんだ
I want to hold you tight,
噛み締めたいんだ
I want to savor it,
追いこしたいんだ
I want to overtake,
いまはかわいいよ クリスマス！
now it's cute, Christmas!
でいじょうぶが大事です
Being all right is important,
まいやる心抑えて
suppressing my eager heart.
調子気味に乗りましょう
Let's get in tune,
やっぱり人柄すぐ慣れる
as expected, personalities quickly get used to it.
青いふたりのヘブン
A blue pair's heaven,
恋いのに鳴る夢は
the dream of becoming lovers
レア行かい
is rare and lively.
徳利のノートレースして
Tracing the tokkuri's note,
空をかけまわり揺れる思いの
running through the sky, swaying feelings,
下の軽目には 恋の音だけ膨らんで
beneath, only the sound of love swells,
すごいベニューをつくるとやぼうなら
if it's an ambition to make an amazing venue,
まぁとにかく果実を味わってみましょう
well, anyway, let's taste the fruit.
高まりたいんだ
I want to get hyped,
味わいたいんだ
I want to taste it,
おたけびたいんだ
I want to shout out loud.
そんな夢を見てクリスマス
Dreaming of such a dream, Christmas.
だいこしおしんは危険です
Being too pushy is dangerous,
むかつく午後は深呼吸
on an irritating afternoon, take a deep breath.
豊かな音の聞き取りましょう
Let's listen to the rich sounds,
切れる人は甘ってる
those who snap are acting spoiled.
ミルクなささきは...
The milky whisper is...
逃避する愛イメージして
imagining an escaping love.
街は飛び跳ねよろず神さ
The town is hopping, oh myriad gods,
おてんばのほっぺたに
on tomboy cheeks,
いばいのお願いが詰まってる
packed with earnest wishes.
絶望しやないひとり恐れないで
Don't despair, don't be afraid alone,
まっすぐゴールを突き進めましょ
let's push straight toward the goal!
遠い憧れヘプン
A distant longing heaven,
時々見失う恋は
love that I sometimes lose sight of,
胸の涙の欠片入れずしよ
put the fragments of tears in my heart.
ゆうづかたつけよ
Let's settle the evening,
揺れる思いの下の
under swaying feelings,
カニクには恋のお医者だけ膨らんで
love's doctor swells...
すごい迷うウルトヤボウならバとにクルツカオコミましょ
If you have wild ambitions, let's dive into...
噛み締めたいんだ今頑張んしよ
I want to bite into it, let's do our best now!
噛み締めたいんだ動かしたいんだ今頑張んしよ
I want to bite, I want to roll, let's do our best!
修行しよういあいしよう
Let's train, let's do iai!
いあいしよくりぽお
Let's cherish each other, creer...
いあいしよう
Let's train together!
口づけを かわした日は
The day we exchanged a kiss,
ママの顔さえも 見れなかった
I couldn't even look at my mom's face.
ポケットのコイン あつめて
Gathering the coins in my pocket,
ひとつずつ 夢を かぞえたね
one by one, we counted our dreams, right?
ほら あれは 二人の かくれが
Look, that was our hiding place,
ひみつの メモリー oh
our secret memory, oh...
どこで こわれたの oh フレンズ
Where did it break, oh friends?
うつむく 日は みつめあって
On days we looked down, gazing at each other,
指を つないだら oh フレンズ
when we linked fingers, oh friends,
時が とまる 気 が した
it felt like time stood still.
ねえ 君は 覚えてる
Hey, do you remember?
夕映えに よくにあう あの曲
That song that fits the evening glow so well,
黙りこむ 君が いつも
the song you always fell silent to,
悲しくて 口ずさんだ のに
even though you hummed it sadly.
今は 流れて セピアに
Now it flows into sepia tones,
染まる メロディー oh
a melody dyeing away, oh...
二度と もどらない oh フレンズ
Never to return again, oh friends,
他人 よりも 遠く 見えて
looking farther away than strangers,
いつも 走ってた oh フレンズ
always running, oh friends,
あの 瞳が いとおしい
those eyes are so dear to me.
いつも 走ってた oh フレンズ
Always running, oh friends,
あの 瞳が いとおしい
those eyes are so dear to me.
どこで壊れたの オーベ
Where did it break, oh well...
うつむく日はら 見つめあって
On days we look down, we gaze at each other
指を繋いだら オーベ
If we link our fingers, oh well...
時が止まる気がした
It felt like time had stopped
二度と戻れない オーベ
We can never go back, oh well...
他人よりも遠く見えて
Looking more distant than strangers
いつも走ってた オーベ
We were always running, oh well...
あのひとりが愛しい
That solitude is so dear
Chu Chu Yeah! Please me!
Chu Chu Yeah! Without you
あー！なんてことだ 細やかな過ち
Ah! What a trivial mistake,
自分のことにタラッタラッタ手焼く
I'm just fumbling over myself.
どうして突然？逃げ切ったっていいでしょ？
Why suddenly? It's okay to run away, right?
だけどなんだか気まぐれモードになり
But somehow I'm in a whimsical mood,
そんな気分になっちゃって
and I've gotten into that kind of mood.
始まりはそんな風で
It started like that,
つまらなさそうないようで
seemingly uninteresting,
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら
but now, open the door, look—
声が聴こえるよ
I can hear a voice.
さあ！行こう！
Come on! Let's go!
どこへでも
Anywhere!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
(Please stay with me)
どんな試練も怖くないその魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trials with that magic.
(なんてったってコングラチュレーション！)
(Congratulations, no matter what!)
初めて出逢う世界に花束を贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet to the world we meet.
(Made in society)
ただこの瞬間結ばれたよ
Just in this moment, we are connected.
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション？
A mismatched communication?
でも別に構わない
But I don't really mind
明日から平和なら！
if it's peaceful from tomorrow!
Chu Chu Yeah! Without you!
あー！どうしてまた素直になれなくて
Ah! Why can't I be honest again?
自分のことでチュルッチュルッチュルッチュ火吹く
I'm blowing fire over myself.
ギアはそのままでピッチ上げ続けていこう
Let's keep the gear as is and increase the speed.
だけどなんだかタソガレモードになり
But somehow I'm in a melancholy mood,
いつかを思い出して
and I remember someday.
独りでいても嫌じゃない誰にも頼らなくてもいい
I don't mind being alone, needing no one.
でも扉の向こう騒がしい声が聴きたいよ
But I want to hear the noisy voice past the door.
今！行こう！
Now! Let's go!
どこへでも
Anywhere!
僕は君を背中に乗せて空を舞うよ！
I'll carry you on my back and fly in the sky!
(Please fly with me)
いつか心が離れてもその時は笑ってて
Even if our hearts drift apart, keep smiling.
(なんてったってコングラチュレーション！)
(Congratulations, no matter what!)
守りたいこの世界に青空のラプソディ
I want to protect this world, a blue sky rhapsody.
(Make me rhapsodic!)
ただいつまでも奏でていてよ
Just keep playing it forever.
凸凹なコンビネーション？
A bumpy combination?
でも別に大丈夫さ
But it's okay anyway.
明日もまだ平和だ！
Tomorrow will still be peaceful!
ほんの小さな傷を太陽にさらして
Exposing small wounds to the sun,
分け合った、君と痛さは熱さの中に溶けてく！
sharing pain with you, melting in the heat!
Chu Chu Yeah! 粋なビート弾く僕ら！
Chu Chu Yeah! We're snapping to a stylish beat!
Please me! 手を叩いて
Please me! Clap your hands!
Chu Chu Yeah! ブギーなリズムではしゃぐふたり！
Chu Chu Yeah! Two people playing in a boogie rhythm!
Without you! 飛び跳ねてさ
Without you! Jumping up!
Chu Chu Yeah! 粋なビート弾く僕ら！
Chu Chu Yeah! We're snapping to a stylish beat!
Please me! 手を叩いて
Please me! Clap your hands!
Chu Chu Yeah! ブギーなリズムではしゃぐみんな！
Chu Chu Yeah! Everyone playing in a boogie rhythm!
(どこまでも！)
(Anywhere!)
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
(Please stay with me)
どんな試練も怖くないその魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trials because of that magic.
(なんてったってコングラチュレーション！)
(Congratulations, no matter what!)
君と出会い世界は花束に溢れた
Meeting you, the world is overflowing with bouquets.
(Made in society)
ただその瞬間結ばれたよ
Just in this moment, we are connected.
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション？
A mismatched communication?
でも別に構わない
But I don't really mind
明日から平和なら
if it's peaceful from tomorrow.
Chu Chu Yeah! Please me!
息をきらし
Out of breath,
Without you!
几帳面なビート弾く僕ら
With our precise beats playing out,
手を叩いて
clapping our hands,
独特のリズムで弾みだすんだ
springing to life with a unique rhythm!
どこでだって
No matter where we are,
僕は君の翼に なれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to be your wings!
例え何度でも怖くない その魔法があるからね
Even if I stumble, I'm not afraid, because that magic is here.
君と出会い世界は 花束にあふれたんだ
Meeting you filled the world with bouquets of flowers.
ただその瞬間の すべてだよ
It's all in that very single moment.
ジグザグコミュニケーション
Zigzag communication,
でも別に気にならない
but I don't really mind at all.
明日が平和ならラララ
As long as tomorrow is peaceful, la la la.
瞳を閉じたとき 見える世界中
Closing my eyes, the world I see all around...
チュウ
Chu!
やりきった！やりきりました！
We did it! We really did it!
ねぇ、間違えたけど、でもね、気付かれてないから大丈夫！
I made a mistake, but nobody noticed, so it's fine!
なんか、私さ、私もう間違えまし...あれ？大丈夫？みんな大丈夫？
Wait, did I mess up too? Are you guys okay?
あれ？みんな大丈夫？大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫...！
Wait, is everyone okay? It's fine, it's fine!
えー、というわけで、今日はね、お誕生日の記念ライブに可愛い後輩2人に来てもらいました！
So today, for my birthday live, I invited two cute junior guests!
ありがとうございます！先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Thank you so much! Happy birthday, Senpai!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
えー、でもね、プログロのライブ見てさ、完成度が高すぎて...
Seeing Progro's live, the completion level was so high...
一緒にできないって思ったけど...今回頑張っちゃいました！
I thought we couldn't do it together, but we worked hard this time!
え、よかったね！ よかった、よかった！
Oh, I'm so glad! That's wonderful!
なんか、ソロデビューしてからの目標が、先輩と一緒にステージで歌って踊ることだったから...
My goal since solo debut was to sing and dance on stage with you...
それが今日叶ったんだよ！やったーーー！！！よかったね！
And it came true today! Yay! I'm so glad!
えーじゃあちょっと最後に可愛くポーズを決めて、写真撮って終わりにしようかなと思います。
Let's strike a cute final pose and take a photo to wrap up!
全力でみんなそれぞれ可愛いポーズね！わかりました！
Let's all do our absolute cutest poses! Got it!
ふりじゃないよ？可愛いね？可愛い？可愛いよね？
This isn't a joke, right? It's cute, right?
せーの！...あー！ちょっと待って！二人とも、え、可愛くないの！？
Ready, go! ...Ah, wait! Aren't you guys cute?!
無垢なハート開いたら すぐもっと
When a pure heart opens up, even more
声合わせて
voices come together!
キラキラしている自分をつかもう
Let's grasp our sparkling selves!
大好きなことしよう
Let's do what we love most!
勝ちが負けたなんて 関係ない止まないで
Whether we win or lose doesn't matter, don't stop!
手を取って繋いで へいじゃー！パーティを始めよう
Holding hands and connecting, hey! Let the party begin!
Get dance 123, Realize! そびえ立つとみんなで 絶対あきらめたくないから
Get dance 123, Realize! We definitely won't give up together!
Let's spin do my best 明日はきっとながやいている
Let's spin, do my best, tomorrow will surely shine bright!
土から合わせて ときめき探し行く 2日にゴロクリパラ
Aligning our steps, we go searching for excitement!
強くよししている自分を
The self striving so strongly...
変えよう みんながついているよ
Let's change it, everyone is right by your side!
無口なハート開いたら
Opening a silent heart,
進め声合わせて
let's go forward, combining our voices.
さあ勇気を出して
Come on, muster up your courage,
hey clap 夢が始まる
hey clap, the dream begins.
let's dance run with me 未来へ
Let's dance run with me to the future,
そうずっとみんなで
always together with everyone.
let's dance run with me 未来へ
Let's dance run with me to the future,
そうずっとみんなで
always together with everyone,
絶対あきらめたくないから
because I definitely don't want to give up!
let's spin do my face 明日は
Let's spin do my face, tomorrow
もっと輝いている
will shine even brighter.
希望をかかげて ドキドキ探して
Raising our hopes, searching with a pounding heart,
すれ違いの物語プリパラ
the story of our misunderstandings, Pripara!
うまくいかないとかすれ違いばかりで
When things don't go well and there are only misunderstandings,
ダメになりそうな時は 一緒に
when we're about to fail, together
ふたつ折り夢を叶えよう
let's make our dreams come true.
笑顔受け取ろう そう一緒に
Let's receive smiles together,
歌いたいね一緒に踊りたい
I want to sing and dance with you.
絶対あきらめないよ let's go
I will never give up, let's go!
let's dance 1, 2, 3! 未来へ
Let's dance 1, 2, 3! To the future,
そうずっとみんなで
always together with everyone,
絶対あきらめたくないから
because I definitely don't want to give up!
let's sing do my best! 明日は
Let's sing do my best! Tomorrow
きっと輝いている
will surely shine brighter.
力合わせて トキメキ探してく
Combining our strength, searching for excitement,
つかみ取れプリパラ
let's grab it, Pripara!
let's dance 1, 2, 3! 未来へ
Let's dance 1, 2, 3! To the future,
そうずっとみんなで
always together with everyone,
絶対あきらめたくないから
because I definitely don't want to give up!
let's spin do my face 明日は
Let's spin do my face, tomorrow
きっと輝いている
will surely shine brighter.
力合わせて トキメキ探してく
Combining our strength, searching for excitement,
つかみ取れプリパラ
let's grab it, Pripara!
let's dance 1, 2, 3! 未来へ
Let's dance 1, 2, 3! To the future,
そうずっとみんなで
always together with everyone,
絶対あきらめたくないから
because I definitely don't want to give up!
let's sing do my best! 明日は
Let's sing do my best! Tomorrow
きっと輝いている
will surely shine brighter.
ちょっとねコメントと30秒くらい下がるんだって
They said comments lag by about 30 seconds.
そうなんだ またあとで
Is that so? See you later!
1本で仕掛けること お邪魔します
Launch in one go, excuse us!
いやマジでさ Realize! 本当にこれ良かったんだしさ
Seriously, Realize! was genuinely so good.
もう土下座だよ 土下座にしよう
We should just dogeza. Let's do dogeza!
いや、もう土下座でいいよ。あとで あるから。土下座で届けられるようになったの
No, dogeza is fine. There's more later. We can deliver it with dogeza now.
土下座で推して 土下座でやるんだ。みてね
Push with dogeza, do it with dogeza. Watch us!
土下座で また会いましょう。はじかんない時間ない
Let's meet again with dogeza. There's no time!
え、ないの？ ポーズ、ポーズとって行くよ。え、おもしろいポーズでしょ
Eh, none? Strike a pose and go. Eh, an interesting pose, right?
おもしろいポーズね。せーの、3、2、1
An interesting pose. Ready, 3, 2, 1...
うわー！無理無理無理無理無理！
Whoa! No no no no no!
提案です! あたし始めない? なんてね
Proposal! Why don't you and I begin? Just kidding.
トーストかじって 交差点でぶつかる
Biting into toast, bumping into each other at the intersection.
そういうんじゃないけど 予感はしてたよ きっとね
It's not really like that, but I had a hunch. Definitely, right?
運命だね 逢えるって信じてた
It's destiny, I believed we would meet.
君専用の笑顔 スタンドバイオッケー!
My smile for you is standby okay!
愚痴がでたり ため息ついたり
Grumbling, sighing,
あるよねわかるよ
I understand, it happens, right?
君が寂しくて 泣いているなら イライラしてたまらないなら
If you're lonely and crying, if you're so frustrated you can't take it,
あたしの出番だな! その手をとって連れて行くよ
it's my turn! I'll take your hand and take you away.
ようこそ! 無敵なテーマパーク もういっそ全部忘れちゃえ!
Welcome! To an invincible theme park, just forget everything already!
とりあえずはあたしだけ見て 底なしの沼だぜ
For now, just look at me, it's a bottomless swamp.
ちょっと考えられないくらい 愛をあげる 君が好きだ
I'll give you more love than you can imagine, I love you!
提案です! あたし始めない? なんてね
Proposal! Why don't you and I begin? Just kidding.
どうやらフラッグは まだ立っていないみたいだ
It seems like the flag hasn't been raised yet.
そんなの気にしない 一直線にtrue end
I don't care about that, straight to the true end.
きっとね 安定だね お決まりのツーショット
Definitely, stable, a classic two-shot.
2人きりの空間 スタンドバイオッケー! 舞い上がっちゃって
A space just for the two of us, standby okay! Flying high,
あとで反省会 あるよねわかるよ
having a reflection meeting later. I understand, it happens, right?
脳内占拠して眠れないなら ソワソワしてたまらないなら
If it occupies your brain and you can't sleep, if you're restless and can't take it,
いつだって、おいでよ
come anytime!
少しずつ積み上げていこうよ ようこそ!
Let's stack it up little by little. Welcome!
無限のパーリータイム もういっそずっと一緒にいようね
To an infinite party time, let's just be together forever already!
とことんまで笑っていてね もっと知って欲しいんだぞ
Keep laughing until the end, I want you to know me more.
そっと掴んだシャツの裾 最上級をプレゼントしよう
The hem of the shirt I gently grabbed, I'll present you with the best class.
どうやらフラグはまだ立っていないみたいだ
It seems no flags have been raised yet!
どんなの気にしない 一直線に震え
No matter what, I don't care, trembling in a straight line
既定ね 安定だね お決まりの処方
Established, stable, right? Our usual remedy
ふたりきりの空間 三敗オッケーイ
A space for just the two of us, three losses is okay!
舞い上がっちゃって あとで反省会
Soaring high, then a self-reflection meeting later
あるよね わかるよ
It happens, right? I understand!
脳内説教して 眠れないなら
If you're lecturing yourself in your head and can't sleep,
ソワソワしてたまらないなら いつだっておいれよ 少しずつ積み上げていこう
If you're too restless, anytime is fine, let's pile it up little by little
ようこそ無限のパラダイス もっとずっと一緒にいよ
Welcome to an infinite paradise, let's stay together even longer
とことんまで わがままでいてね
To the absolute end, please remain selfish
もっと自信が欲しいんだぞ ちょっと掴んだ シャツの裾
I want more confidence, grabbing the hem of your shirt a little bit
体重急増をプレゼントしよう
Let's present a sudden weight gain!
歌うこと考えなくてもいいよ 暖かなしを続けよ
You don't have to think about singing, just keep having fun
繋いだ今日が 明日になってくんだ
The day we connected becomes tomorrow
夜空の旋風速 全身で とんでもない景色見に行こう
Whirlwind in the night sky, whole body, let's go see incredible scenery
乗り掛かっている 自覚あるでしょ
You know you're already in this, right?
そんじゃそこらの遊びじゃもう満足できないくらい
To the point where ordinary play is no longer enough
夢中になれる 夢中にさせる
Making you get absorbed, making you get lost in it
ようこそ無限のパラダイス もっとずっと忘れちゃえ
Welcome to an infinite paradise, let's forget it all even longer
リアライズは 私だけに見て
Realize it, look only at me
そんじゃなしの沼だぞ ちょっと考えられないくらい
It's a bottomless swamp, to the point you can't even think
愛をあげる 君が好きだ
Giving you love, I like you!
時間なんて関係ないさ 今だってほら 笑ってんじゃん
Time doesn't matter, right now, look, we're laughing, aren't we?
案外始まんないなんてね
As expected, it won't even start...
突然降る夕立 ああ傘もないや嫌
A sudden evening shower falls, I realized I didn't have an umbrella.
空のご機嫌なんたらないやいや
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだろ
When it's time for the seasons to change, what are you supposed to wear?
春と秋どこいっちゃったんだろ
Spring and autumn didn't come at all.
息も出来ない 情報の圧力
The pressure of information, suffocating
眩暈の螺旋だ わたしはどこにいる
A spiral of vertigo, don't know where I am.
こんなにこんなに息の音がするのに 変だね 世界の音がしない
I can hear myself breathing so loud, but why? I can't hear the world's sounds.
足りない 足りない 誰にも気づかれない
It's not enough, no one knows I'm here.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed when I couldn't make a scribble of a sound.
「ありのまま」なんて 誰に見せるんだ
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
So I'm singing just like the fool I am. Let's lay it all out to the stars!
エリクサーに張り替える作業もなんとなくなんだ
Even with the Elixir strings, the sound is not satisfactory.
欠けた爪を少し触る
Caress broken nails
半径300mmの体で必死に鳴いている
Playing the guitar desperately with the body radius of 300 millimeters.
音楽にとっちゃ ここが地球だな
For music, there is the earth.
空気を掴んで 空を殴るよ
Grab the air and hit the sky
なににも起きない わたしは無力さ
Nothing happened, I was helpless.
だけどさ その手で この鉄を弾いたら
But to pluck a string with that hand
何かが変わって見えた...ような。
I can feel like something's changed... it seems to be.
突然降る夕立
A sudden evening shower falls,
あぁ傘もないや嫌
Ah, I don't even have an umbrella.
空のご機嫌なんてもう知らない
Who cares how the sky's feeling anyway?
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだろ
When the seasons change, what should I wear?
春と秋どっかいっちゃったんだろ
Did spring and autumn just disappear?
息も出来ない 情報の圧力
The pressure of information, suffocating.
めまいの螺鈿だ わたしはどこにいる
A spiral of vertigo, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
I can hear myself breathing so loud, so loud...
変だね 世界の音がしない
But why? I can't hear the sounds of the world...
足らない 足らない 誰にも気づかれない
Not enough, no one even notices me.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed when I couldn't make a scribble of a sound.
「ありのまま」なんて 誰に見せるんだ
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So I'm singing just like the fool I am.
蒼い惑星 ひとりぼっち いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
Alone on the blue planet, I heard a lot of voices.
回り続けて幾億年 一瞬でもいいから... あぁ聞いて訊かせて
The planet keeps spinning for billions of years. Even for a moment... hear it. Listen to it.
わたし わたし わたしはここにいる
I, I, I'm right here.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed when I couldn't make a scribble of a sound.
なにかになりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to be anyone, anything at all.
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So I'm singing just like the fool I am.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed when I couldn't make a scribble of a sound.
なにかになりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to be anyone, anything at all.
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
So I'm singing just like the fool I am.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
ねね先輩お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Nene-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！やったー！
Thank you so much! Yay!
というわけで、
And so,
リグラスから奏ちゃんに来てもらいました！
we invited Kanade-chan from ReGLOSS!
新年金からでしょ、やったーやったー！
(Kanade: Since it's the new year... Yay, yay!)
今回はね、普段の奏ちゃんたちのしゃべりと歌のギャップが大好きで
This time, I love the gap between Kanade-chan's usual talking and singing,
はぁ～、普段これじゃん、普段これだけど歌うと急にさ、
(Kanade: Haah~ Normally it's like this, but when singing all of a sudden...)
なんかさ、切ないエモいみたいな
(Nene: ...somehow melancholic and emotional)
うれし、ねね先輩にそう言ってもらえるととっても嬉しい！
(Kanade: I'm so happy, to hear Nene-senpai say that makes me so happy!)
本当は、はい、そのイメージがめっちゃ好きで
(Nene: Actually, yes, I really love that image...)
一緒にそういう ちょっとギャップが出る曲歌いたいなと思って。
and wanted us to sing a song with that kind of gap together.
ねね先輩もめっちゃかっこよかったです、ありがとうございます。
(Kanade: Nene-senpai was also super cool, thank you!)
最高！
(Nene: Awesome!)
あとなんか、髪の毛の色もさ、同じ金髪から
(Kanade: And also, our hair color... from the same blonde)
確かに、同じ金髪からグラデーション？
(Nene: True! From the same blonde to a gradation?)
ちょっとシンクロしてるかなと思って、お揃いにしてみました。
(Kanade: I thought we were somewhat in sync, so I matched it.)
受け取ってくれてありがとう！一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！
(Nene & Kanade: Thank you for accepting! We're so glad we could sing together!)
奏ちゃんのね、ダンスの覚え方がかわいいんだよ。
(Nene: Kanade-chan's way of memorizing dances is so cute.)
え、そう、なんか忍者忍者、忍者忍者忍者忍者って
(Kanade: Eh, yeah, like ninja ninja, ninja ninja ninja ninja...)
覚える、覚えるときこうなってて、こう忍者忍者って
(Kanade: Remembering it like, when memorizing it goes like this, ninja ninja...)
ありましたよね、前回もめっちゃ笑顔だったよ。
(Nene: That happened, right? You had a huge smile last time too.)
えーっと、じゃあ最後に、ちょっとどうしようかな。
(Nene: Um, well, lastly, what should we do?)
ギャップのある感じで、セリフを、おまかせしてください。
(Kanade: With that gap-like vibe, lines... leave it to me.)
おまかせしてくださいなの？はい！ちょっとできるかな、でも、ちょっとかっこいいエモい感じで、かっこいい感じで、おまかせしてください。
(Nene: Leave it to it? Kanade: Yes! I can do it, maybe...)
行きますよ、いこっ。
(Kanade: Here we go, let's go.)
今なんて何やった今？
(Nene: What did I just do just now?)
ちょっとかっこいいエモい感じで。
(Nene: In a slightly cool, emotional way.)
桜が咲くよ 見慣れたいつもの坂道に
The cherry blossoms are blooming, on the familiar road we always take
あぁ 別れを
Ah, it's time to say goodbye
泣いて笑ったあの日々
Those days we spent crying and laughing
なんだか昨日のことのように
They feel like they were just yesterday
この道はそう 未来へ続く道
This road, yes, it's a road that continues into the future
そんな気がしたの
That's what I felt
例年より早い開花予想を キミは嬉しがってた
You were so happy about the forecast that cherry blossoms would bloom early
泣いて笑った
Crying and laughing,
あの日々
those days...
なんだか昨日のことのよう
feeling just like yesterday.
桜が咲くよ
The cherry blossoms bloom
見慣れたいつもの坂道に
On the familiar, usual hill path,
ああ 別れを
Ah, bidding farewell—
泣いて笑ったあの日々は
those days of laughing and crying
なんだか昨日のことのように
feel almost like yesterday.
この道はそう 未来へ続く道
This path is, yes, a path leading to the future,
そんな気がしたの
or so I felt.
例年より早い
The forecast for earlier blooming
開花予想を
than usual this year
キミは嬉しがってた
you were so happy about.
私は笑って
I smiled and
「そうだね」って言った
said, "That's right."
あと少ししたらもう
Even though a little while longer and
ここには戻れないのに
we won't be able to return here,
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを
if I were to confess the feelings
キミに打ち明けるとしたらなんて
I can't put into words to you, I wonder what...
伝えよう 最初で最後
I'll tell you, my first and last.
いつか一緒に帰った道は
The path we walked home together back then
私にとって特別な思い出
will always be a special memory to me.
忘れないよ
I won't ever forget.
さよならメモリーズ
Goodbye, memories.
春が来たら それぞれの道を
When spring comes, each of us taking our own path,
また会える日を願って
hoping for the day we can meet again,
「さよなら」小さくつぶやいた
I whispered a quiet "Goodbye."
空はあの日と変わらず青くて
The sky is just as blue as it was that day,
だからちょっと泣けた
so I cried a little.
わざと遠回りしたの
I took a detour on purpose,
少しでも長くキミの近くにいたくて
wanting to stay by your side for even a little longer.
私はおどけて「まちがえた！」って言った
I played it off and said, "Oops, I made a mistake!"
キミは笑う その顔が
You smiled, and that face of yours
まぶしくて目をそらした
was so dazzling I looked away.
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを
Holding all the feelings I can't put into words
胸に抱いてこの道を歩いた
in my chest, I walked down this path.
覚えている あの時キミは
I remember, back then,
私の名前を呼んでくれた
you called out my name.
二人 夕暮れの帰り道で
The two of us on the sunset way home—
忘れないよ
I won't ever forget.
さよならメモリーズ
Goodbye, memories.
出逢えた事 感謝してると
I'm so grateful for having met you
初めて見た 満開の桜
under the cherry blossoms in full bloom we first saw together.
あれからどれくらい変われたんだろう
I wonder how much I've changed since then.
一目見た時に思ったんだ
The moment I first saw you, I thought,
この人のこと好きになりそうって
"I think I'm going to fall in love with this person."
何でか分からないや
I don't know why.
それからの毎日はとても楽しくて
Every single day after that was so much fun,
でも同じくらい辛かったんだ
but it was also just as painful.
ごめんね なんかうまく言えないや
I'm sorry, I just can't say it right.
だから私キミとなんていうか
So, you and I... how should I put it?
今のまま さよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye just like this.
友達のままじゃもう嫌なの
I don't want to stay just friends anymore.
言おうと思っていた
That's what I intended to tell you.
私 キミの、キミのことずずっと
I've always, always loved you,
前から好きでした
ever since before.
I've loved you all along.
ああ やっと言えた
Ah... I finally said it.
一目見た時に思ったんだ
The moment I first saw you, I thought,
この人のこと好きになりそうって
"I think I'm going to fall in love with this person."
何でか分からないや
I don't know why.
それからの毎日はとても楽しくて
Every single day after that was so much fun,
でも同じくらい辛かったんだ
but it was also just as painful.
ごめんね なんかうまく言えないや
I'm sorry, I just can't say it right.
だから私キミとなんていうか
So, you and I... how should I put it?
今のまま さよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye just like this.
友達のままじゃもう嫌なの
I don't want to stay just friends anymore.
言おうと思っていた
That's what I intended to tell you.
私 キミの、キミのことずずっと
I've always, always loved you,
今のまま
Just like this—
さよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye.
友達のままじゃもう嫌なの
I don't want to remain just friends.
言おうと思っていた
That's what I wanted to tell you.
私 キミの、キミのことずずっと
I've always, always loved you
前から好きでした
ever since before.
今のまま
Just like this—
さよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye.
友達のままじゃもう嫌なの
I don't want to remain just friends.
言おうと思っていた
That's what I wanted to tell you.
私 キミの、キミのことずずっと
I've always, always loved you
前から好きでした
ever since before.
ああ やっと言えた
Ah... I finally said it.
いつだって君は笑われ者だ
You are always someone who gets laughed at,
挙句に雨に降られて
getting caught in the rain in the end,
お気に入りの傘は風で飛んでって
your favorite umbrella blown away by the wind,
そこ野良はご苦労様と足を踏みつけてた
and a stray cat stepping on you, saying \"Good work.\"
いつもどおり君は嫌われ者だ
As always, you are someone who is hated,
なんにもせずとも遠ざけられて
kept at a distance without doing anything wrong,
努力をしてみるけど
and even though you try your best,
その理由なんて「なんとなく?」で
the reason is just \"for no particular reason?\"
君は途方にくれて悲しんでた
Leaving you at a loss and feeling so sad.
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
If that's the case, you can just use my voice.
人によっては理解不能でなんて耳障り ひどい声だって言われるけど
Though some might find it incomprehensible and call it a harsh, grating voice,
きっと君の力になれるからあたしを歌わせてみて
it can surely become your strength, so try having me sing!
そう君の 君だけの言葉でさ 紡いで 連ねて
Yes, with your words, your words alone—weave them together, string them along,
あたしがその思想を叫ぶから 描いて 理想を
because I will shout out those thoughts. Paint your ideals,
その想いは誰にも触れさせない ガラクタの声はそして響く
and I won't let anyone touch those feelings. Then the voice of odds and ends resounds,
ありのままを不器用に繋いで 目一杯大声を上げる
awkwardly connecting your true self, raising your voice at the top of your lungs.
いつからか君は人気者だ
Before you knew it, you became popular,
たくさんひとに持て囃され あたしも鼻が高い
adored by many people, and I felt so proud too.
でもいつからか君は変わった 冷たくなって だけど寂しそうだった
But somewhere along the way, you changed—becoming cold, yet looking so lonely.
「もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ 僕は僕自身なんだよって」
"We've had enough of mechanical voices, I am my own person!"
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって あたしを嫌った
At last, you couldn't hold it back anymore and came to hate me.
君の背後で誰かが言う 虎の威を借るキツネの癖にって
Someone says behind your back, "Just a fox riding on a tiger's coattails!"
ねぇ 君は一人で泣いてたんだね
Hey, you were crying all alone, weren't you?
聴こえる? この声
Can you hear it? This voice
あたしがその雑言をかき消すから
drowning out all those harsh words.
わかってる 本当は 君が誰より優しいってことを
I know, the truth is you are kinder than anyone else.
ガラクタの声はそして歌った 他の誰でもない君のために
And so the voice of odds and ends sang, solely for you, no one else.
響いてく 限界を超えて
Resounding, surpassing all limits,
二人はどんなにたくさんの言葉を思いついたことだろう
how many countless words we must have thought of together.
だけど今は何ひとつ思いつかなくて
Yet now, not a single word comes to mind,
だけど何もかも分かった
yet somehow, we understood everything.
そうか きっとこれは夢だ
Ah, surely this is a dream—
永遠に覚めない 君と逢えた そんな夢
a dream where I met you, one that will never wake.
ガラクタの幸せ そう中身はおなじまま
The happiness of odds and ends, with its contents just as they were.
どれだけ呼んでももう動かない
No matter how much I call out, it no longer moves.
望んだはずの結末に 君は泣き叫べ
Cry and scream out at the very ending you wished for.
嘘だろ 嘘だろ ってそう泣き叫べ
"You've got to be kidding, this isn't real"—you scream and cry like that.
僕は無力だからひとつだって救えやしない
Because I am powerless, I can't save even a single thing.
想いは
These feelings...
いつだって君は嘲笑れ者
You're always someone who gets laughed at.
挙句に雨に降られ お気に召すまま
Whatever you do, it never goes well...
突然にその色を 大きく変える
Suddenly changing its color drastically—
悲しみ 喜び
sorrow and joy.
すべてをひとりずつを 一つはしご
Connecting everyone, one by one, step by step.
言葉は歌になりこの世界を 再び駆け巡る君のために
Words become a song, traveling around this world once more for you.
その声に 意志を宿して今 思いが響く
Imbuing that voice with will, my thoughts echo now.
はい、ポルカがハモリじゃないよ、みんな。
Hey, Polka isn't the harmony, everyone!
ねねの声だよー。
It's Nene's voice!
というわけで、えっと、ゲストにいっぱい来ていただきまして、いっぱいいろんな歌歌えて楽しかったです。
So, um, we had lots of guests come, and it was so fun singing lots of different songs.
ちなみに、フレンズはママのチョイスです。みんな、ママのチョイスかなって言ってから大正解です。
By the way, "Friends" was Mama's choice. Everyone guessed it was Mama's choice, so that's spot on!
じゃあ、告知行きたいと思います！まずは、こちら！
Now, I'd like to go to the announcements! First, this one!
桃鈴ねね誕生日記念2026グッズが発売されます！まずはこちら！
Momosuzu Nene's 2026 Birthday Commemorative Goods are on sale! First, this one!
ワイドラバーマット！
Wide rubber mat!
うえむずかんでねねがね、上を摘みながら、あのみんなに「おねがーい」ってしてる感じのイラストで、イラストはまるろ先生描き下ろしで横幅がめっちゃ広いので、キーボードとかマウス置いてデスクで使ってください！
It's an illustration of Nene pinching the top and asking everyone "Please~", drawn exclusively by Maruro-sensei! It's super wide, so please use it on your desk with your keyboard and mouse!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
さっきのね、同じキービジュアルを使った前面はTシャツ、後ろ面は尊き桃鈴って書いてあるTシャツです。
Using the same key visual from earlier, the front is a T-shirt, and the back is a T-shirt that says "Precious Momosuzu".
前ね、あの出したやっぱり桃鈴に続く尊い桃鈴のTシャツが出来上がりました！
Earlier we released a precious Momosuzu T-shirt following that one, and now this is ready too!
そして次はこちら！ランダムミニアクリルスタンドキーホルダー！
And next is this! Random Mini Acrylic Stand Keychain!
いろんな衣装のねねがね、可愛いポーズをしています！イラストは花森ゆのき先生に描いてもらえました！台座とボールチェーンがついてるので、ミニアクスタとしても使えるし、キーホルダーとしても使えます！
Nene in various outfits is striking cute poses! The illustrations were drawn by Hanamori Yunoki-sensei! It comes with a stand and a ball chain, so you can use it as a mini acrylic stand or a keychain!
そして次、こちら！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー私服衣装ver.！
And next, this! Plush Toy Keychain Casual Outfit ver.!
これめっちゃこだわって作ってて、もう可愛さ全部盛りのねねね私服衣装のぬいぐるみのキーホルダーになります！
We made this with extreme care, and it's a plush keychain of Nene in her casual outfit packed with all sorts of cuteness!
前のね、前髪とか顔とかすごいこだわって作ったので絶対可愛い自信があるので実物今度見せたいと思います！
We put a lot of care into the bangs and face, so we're confident it's super cute and want to show you the actual item soon!
そして最後！ボイスです！シチュエーションボイス「ねねとぎみのお誕生日」！
And last! Voice! Situation Voice "Nene and Your Birthday"!
ねねがね、みんなのお誕生日もお祝いしてあげたいと思う、しょうがないので。
Nene wants to celebrate everyone's birthdays too, since it can't be helped.
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is here!
数量限定は直筆サインと複製箔押しメッセージ入りポストカード！そして通常版は、箔押しの複製サインとメッセージが入っています！
The limited quantity version is a postcard with a handwritten signature and duplicated hot-stamped message! And the regular version includes a hot-stamped duplicated signature and message!
さらにボイスもついてきます！タイトル「毎日1番に見てほしいの！」ということでねねが幼馴染みのねねがね、みんなに行こうぜ行こうぜって朝から引っかかってくるシチュエーションボイスあります！
Plus, it comes with a voice! Title: "I want you to see me first every day!" There's a situation voice where Nene as a childhood friend pesters everyone from morning to go together!
このあと21時30分から販売開始です！よろしくお願いします！
Sales start at 21:30 right after this! Thank you very much!
そして、オリジナル曲のMVが出ます！リミナル、本日MVは21時15分からを予定しています！
And, the music video for the original song is coming out! "Liminal", today's MV is scheduled for 21:15!
リリースは3月3日の0時から！よろしくお願いします！どんな曲だろうね、今回のライブのタイトルにもなってます！
Release is from 0:00 on March 3rd! Thank you! I wonder what kind of song it is, it's even the title of this live!
そして、超重大告知があります！こちら！
And, there is a super major announcement! Here!
「Peachful Story」モモスズネネのファーストアルバムが、このあと21時、あ、今ちょうど！21時から始まりました！イエーイ！
"Peachful Story", Momosuzu Nene's 1st album, starts at 21:00 right after—oh, right now! It started at 21:00! Yay!
初回盤と通常版2種類あります！
There are two types: the first-run edition and the regular edition!
通常版はこちら！リィチ先生が書いてくれた、通常のやつと、ランダムのアナザージャケットがついてきます！なんとこちら、ドン！
The regular edition is here! It comes with the regular one drawn by Riichi-sensei and a random another jacket! And this, boom!
伊那ちゃんとうーらちゃんに書いてもらえました！マイク持ってるほうが伊那ちゃんで、踊ってるほうがうーらちゃんが書いてくれました！ありがとう！
Ina-chan and Uu-ra-chan wrote/drew them for us! The one holding the mic is by Ina-chan, and the dancing one is by Uu-ra-chan! Thank you!
こちらは数量限定で直筆サインが入っているので、みなさんぜひチェックしてください！
This has a handwritten signature in limited quantities, so everyone please be sure to check it out!
リバーシブル仕様の
With a reversible design,
直筆サイン入りアナザージャケットを
you can choose which side of the autographed
どっちをね、表にして主役にしてもいいですし、
another jacket you want as the main cover,
なんなら2個買っていただいて、両方とも表面にして、ネネとネネをがっちゃんこさせてください。
or better yet, buy two and put Nene and Nene together on both sides!
そして、えーこちらがついてきます。
And, um, this also comes with it.
レコーディングブックと、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのカードはついてきまーす！
A recording book and a card from the Hololive Official Card Game!
ネネのね、どんな感じで歌ってたとか、ここ怒られたとか、そういうのがまとまったノートになってます。
It's a notebook filled with notes on how Nene sang and where she got scolded.
そして、もう一つあります！なんと、こちら！
And there's one more thing! Behold, this!
「ねねねのね」ネネのファーストEP、グッズとして出したね、ネネのCDが復刻になります！イェーイ！
Nene's 1st EP "Nenenenene", the CD released as merch, is getting a reissue! Yay!
これね、あの、意外と、たぶん持ってる人す、少ないんじゃないかなと思います。
I think quite a few people might not actually own this one.
あの、今までのねねのね、あの有名な曲たちが入っていますので、こちらの復刻版もぜひ聞いて、今回のアルバムと一緒に全曲聞いて、覚えて、ほしいなって思います！
It features Nene's famous past songs, so I hope you'll listen to this reissue along with the new album!
さて、さっきリミナルのMVの告知をしたと思うんですけど、どんな曲か聴きたいよね、みんな。
Now, I mentioned the "Liminal" MV earlier, but I bet everyone wants to hear what kind of song it is.
それじゃあ、ねね、今からしっとりと、やっていこうかなと思います。
Well then, Nene is going to perform it nice and mellow now.
それでは聞いてください、「Liminal」。
So please listen to "Liminal".
見つめる
Gazing into
ぐすんだ瞳で
my dull eyes,
光を探して迷ってた
I wandered searching for the light.
いくつのもの痛みに
Bound to countless pains,
縛られたまま 頬を伝う
letting tears trickle down my cheeks—
画面に映る私はどうして 涙の跡が消されているんだろう
Why are the traces of tears erased from the self reflected on the screen?
日び割れた硝子の向こう 笑って作っていた
Beyond the cracked glass, I forced a smile and lived.
誰かがいた 「偽物みたいだ」って
Someone was there, saying, "It looks like a fake,"
「ただの影だ」って 決め付けたって
"It's just a shadow," they decided.
まやかしじゃなくて 私が私でいる理由を
Not an illusion, but the reason why I am myself—
君の笑顔に 貰っていた
I received it from your smile.
そうさ 画面の中 隠せない 消せない 見えない それでも それでも 私は
That's right, inside the screen, unhidden, unerasable, invisible—even so, even so, I...
君の光を追って 閉じこもる暗い硝子の 曇りも払って
Chasing your light, brushing away the fog of the dark glass where I hid,
今 明日を見つけたんだ
I found tomorrow today.
忘れたくない 君がくれた この感情を
I never want to forget this emotion you gave me.
見つめる 姿鏡の奥の
Gazing deep inside the mirror,
涙の跡は見られないけど
the traces of tears cannot be seen, but
磨かれた硝子の向こう 笑って 輝いていたいたいだけで
beyond the polished glass, I just want to keep smiling and shining.
「誰のためだっけ？」 わけ
"Who was this for again?"
声が姿が 誰でもない気がした
My voice, my appearance—it felt like they belonged to no one.
「孤独だって」 また迷い出す 画面の奥の歪みを いつでも いつでも 君は
"I'm alone," I start to wander again. No matter when, no matter what, you...
映す 光の中に 名もない 私の声を見つけてくれてた
inside the reflected light, you always found my nameless voice.
ずっと この声も 姿も 紛れもない私だ
Always... This voice, this appearance, they are undeniably me.
「この声も、姿も、紛れない私だ」
This voice, this form, they are unmistakably me.
「ありのままでいいんだ」
It's okay to just be as I am.
「この気持ちは本物だ」
These feelings are real.
縛られても 触れられなくても
Even if I'm bound, even if I can't touch you,
君が示してくれてたから
because you showed it to me...
いつかこの「私」で
Someday, as this "me",
ずっと光を手繰って
I'll keep reeling in the light,
きっと見つけ出す 誰でもない「君」に会えるまで
until I surely find and meet the irreplaceable "you."
境界線は すぐそこに
The boundary line is right there.
そうさ 画面の向こう 繋ぎたい 越えたい 触れたい それこそ私なんだ
Beyond the screen—to connect, cross, and touch—that is truly me.
君と光になって
Becoming light together with you,
未だ遮る硝子の壁の先まで 届くように 笑っていたい
I want to smile so it reaches beyond the blocking glass wall.
迷いはない 君がくれたこの感情と
With no hesitation, and with this emotion you gave me...